Norman Corwin Papers
Norman Corwin Papers
- Productions of Corwin
  - Radio programs, individual
    - They Fly Through The Air, Words Without Music, episode number unknown
      - Recording
        Presented on February 19, 1939, in the WORDS WITHOUT MUSIC series over CBS. House Jameson narrated. The broadcast won the highest award of the Ohio State Institute for the best dramatic program of the year. Published in THIRTEEN BY CORWIN, and as a separate edition by Vrest Orton. (Envelope 79 of this collection.)
        - They Fly Through The Air Part 1 [disc 1 of 3], 02/19/1939; corwin_0160; Lacquer discs/acetates
          A note on the sleeve's label indicates that additional data is in Envelope 100. On the disc's label is handwritten "Recording of CBS Record" and the printed date of Feb 20, 1939 is crossed off, in pen is written Feb 19, 1939.
        - They Fly Through The Air Part 2 [disc 2 of 3], 02/19/1939; corwin_0161; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - They Fly Through The Air [disc 3 of 3], 01/29/1942; corwin_0162; Lacquer discs/acetates
          This is a two sided disc. Handwritten note on label indicates that this is a production of University of Oregon - Radio Workshop. The date on the disc's label is January 29, 1942.
      - Script (310), 1939; final broadcast script, with annotations and corrections (Box 22)
    - Thirteen By Corwin, as prepared for publication in book form by Henry Holt
      - Typescripts of front and back matter (374), 1941; mockup of title page; typescripts of foreword, glossary (Box 22)
      - Typescripts of programs (1), 1941; typescripts, photocopies, many with extensive annotations and edits; 2 folders (Box 22)
    - This is War
      - Correspondence (101, 128), 1942-1946; undated; 2 folders (Box 23)
      - Correspondence, internal, 1942; memos to/from Robert Heller; lists of episode titles; summary of results of interview with New York residents about what they'd like to know about the war effort, (Box 23)
      - Recording, Program #1: Introduction
        First of 13-part series carried over the combined networks of the U.S., NBC Blue and Red, CBS, and Mutual, on Feb. 14, 1942. Robert Montgomery, then a Navy lieutenant, narrated this opening broadcast. H.L. McClinton produced. Lyn Murray composed and conducted the score. The script appears in the volume THIS IS WAR! published by Dodd, Mead & Co., N.Y., 1942.
        - This is War - Introductory Program Part 1 [disc 1 of 2], Feb 14, 1942; corwin_0183; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - This is War - Introductory Program Part 2 [disc 2 of 2], Feb 14, 1942; corwin_0184; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, Program #2: The White House and the War
        Second of 13-part series. Written by William N. Robson and John Driscoll. Directed by Corwin. Narrated by Paul Muni., and broadcast over the combined networks of America on Feb. 21, 1942. Music was composed and conducted by Leith Stevens. The script was published in THIS IS WAR! Dodd, Mead & Co., 1942.
        - This is War: The White House and the War Part 1 [disc 1 of 2], Feb 21, 1942; corwin_0188; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - This is War: The White House and the War Part 2 [disc 2 of 2], Feb 21, 1942; corwin_0189; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, Program #3: Your Navy
        Third of 13-part series. Written by Maxwell Anderson and directed by Corwin. Starring Fredric March and Douglas Fairbanks, Jr., the latter then a lieutenant in the Navy. Music for the program was composed by Kurt Weill and conducted by Don Voorhees.
        - This is War: Your Navy Part 1 [disc 1 of 2], corwin_0190; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - This is War: Your Navy Part 2 [disc 2 of 2], corwin_0191; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, Program #4: Your Army, 1942
        Fourth in 13-part series. Written by Stephen Vincent Benet, directed by Corwin. Narrated by Tyrone Power. Music composed and conducted by Morton Gould. Broadcast over the combined networks on March 7, 1942. Script appears in the book THIS IS WAR!
        - This Is War: Your Army [disc 1 of 2], 03/07/1942; corwin_0192; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - This Is War: Your Army [disc 2 of 2], 03/07/1942; corwin_0193; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, Program #5: The United Nations
        Fifth in 13-part series. Written by George Faulkner, directed by Corwin. Music composed by Tom Bennett and conducted by Andre Kostelanetz. Broadcast over the four U.S. networks on March 14, 1942. Script among those published in THIS IS WAR! The principal voice was that of the film star, Thomas Mitchell.
        - This Is War: The United Nations [disc 1 of 2], 03/14/1942; corwin_0194; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - This Is War: The United Nations [disc 2 of 2], 03/14/1942; corwin_0195; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, Program #6: You're On Your Own
        Sixth in 13-part series. Written by Philip Wylie, directed by Corwin. Co-starred Ezra Stone and Claude Raines. Broadcast over the 4 U.S. networks on March 21, 1942. Script published in the book THIS IS WAR!
        - This Is War: You're On Your Own [disc 1 of 2], 03/21/1942; corwin_0196; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - This Is War: You're On Your Own [disc 2 of 2], 03/21/1942; corwin_0197; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, Program #7: It's In the Works
        Seventh of 13-part series. Written and directed by Corwin, broadcast over the four U.S. networks on March 28, 1942. Starred were John Garfield, Katherine Locke and John Carradine. Music was composed and conducted by Lyn Murray. Script published in the collection THIS IS WAR!, Dodd, Mead & Co., 1942.
        - This is War - It's in the Works, March 28, 1942; corwin_0185; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, Program #8: Your Air Force
        Eighth in 13-part series. This is the only one of the series that was not directed by Corwin, and was written by Ranald MacDougall, up to that time an NBC page boy. MacDougall submitted his script to Corwin early in the series. It was accepted and scheduled for broadcast from Hollywood on April 4, 1942. James Stewart, then a lieutenant in the air force, and Frank Albertson were the principal players. Music was composed by Charles dant; the program was directed by Glenhall Taylor. MacDougall went on from this script to become a successful writer and director for films in Hollywood. Broadcast over the combined networks. Script published in the collection, THIS IS WAR!
        - This Is War: Your Air Force [disc 1 of 2], 04/04/1942; corwin_0198; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - This Is War: Your Air Force [disc 2 of 2], 04/04/1942; corwin_0199; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, Program #9: The Enemy
        Ninth of 13-part series. Written and directed by Corwin, narrated by Clifton Fadiman, and broadcast over the four major networks of the U.S. on April 11, 1942. Music was composed and conducted by Don Voorhees. The script was published in the book THIS IS WAR!, Dodd, Mead & Co., N.Y. 1942.
        - This is War: The Enemy Part 1 [disc 1 of 2], April 11, 1942; corwin_0186; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - This is War: The Enemy Part 2 [disc 2 of 2], April 11, 1942; corwin_0187; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, Program #11: Smith Against the Axis
        Eleventh in 13-part series. Written by Ranald MacDougall, directed by Corwin, narrated by James Cagney. The music was composed and conducted by Lehman Engel. Broadcast over the combined networks of the U.S. on April 25, 1942. Script included in the volume THIS IS WAR!
        - This Is War: Smith Against the Axis [disc 1 of 2], 04/25/1942; corwin_0200; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - This Is War: Smith Against The Axis [disc 2 of 2], 04/25/1942; corwin_0201; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, Program #12: To The Young
        - This Is War: To the Young [disc 1 of 2], 05/02/1942; corwin_0202; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - This Is War: To the Young [disc 2 of 2], 05/02/1942; corwin_0203; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, Program #13: Yours Received and Contents Noted
        Final episode of 13-part series. Written and directed by Corwin, narrated by Raymond Massey, and presented over the four major networks of the U.S on May 9, 1942. Music was composed and conducted by Tom Bennett, and conducted by Dr. Frank Black. Script published in the collection THIS IS WAR!, Dodd, Mead & Co., 1942.
        - This Is War: Yours Received and Contents Noted [disc 1 of 2], 05/09/1942; corwin_0204; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - This Is War: Yours Received and Contents Noted [disc 2 of 2], 05/09/1942; corwin_0205; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Script, Program #12: To The Young (101), 1942; final broadcast script, with annotations and corrections (Box 23)
    - Tomorrow
      - Recording
        Written by Jerome Lawrence (co-author of AUNTIE MAME and INHERIT THE WIND, &c) and narrated by Corwin for Palestine Appeal. Broadcast on a series entitled PREVIEW THEATER over a Los Angeles radio station on May 7, 1948.
        - Tomorrow [disc 1 of 2], 05/07/1948; corwin_0247; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - Tomorrow [disc 2 of 2], 05/07/1948; corwin_0248; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Transatlantic Call
      This show consisted of a series of international exchange broadcasts originating alternately in England and the United States, and transmitted simultaneously by CBS and the BBC in the U.S. and England. The U.S. episodes were to be written, narrated, directed and produced by Corwin, but due to illness he completed only three episodes (he was replaced on the show by Alan Lomax). The first was NEW ENGLAND (no recording survives), the second was WASHINGTON, D. C., and the third was THE MIDWEST.
      - Recording, Program #2 Washington, D.C.
        Second of three in the series done by Corwin. The original musical score was composed and conducted by Bernard Harrmann. Script unpublished. An unusually large cast (16) participated, including Art Carney, Karl Swenson, Jackson Beck, Joseph Julian, Barry Kroeger, Arnold Moss, Maurice Tarplin, Olive Deering, Kermit Murdock, and Elspeth Eric. Guy della Cioppa was assistant director. Music was composed and conducted by Bernard Herrmann.
        - Transatlantic Call: Washington, D.C. Part 1 [disc 1 of 2], 02/27/1943; corwin_0234; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - Transatlantic Call: Washington, D.C. Part 2 [disc 2 of 2], 02/27/1943; corwin_0235; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Script, Program #2 Washington, D.C., 1943; typescript (Box 23)
      - Publicity, Program #3 The Midwest, 1943 (Box 23)
      - Recording, Program #3 The Midwest
        Third of three in the series done by Corwin. This, the one which Corwin considered the most successful of his three, was broadcast from the studios of WBBM, Chicago, on March 14, 1943. Carl Sandburg appeared on the program in the Chicago studio, and Wendell Willkie spoke from New York. Guy Della Cioppa, later a CBS Vice-president, and Ted Robertson assisted Corwin in the control room. Corwin participated on the air.
        - Transatlantic Call: The Midwest Part 1 [disc 1 of 2], 03/14/1943; corwin_0232; Lacquer discs/acetates (Oversize 7)
        - Transatlantic Call: The Midwest Part 2 [disc 2 of 2], 03/14/1943; corwin_0233; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - The Undecided Molecule, Columbia Presents Corwin, Season 2 #3
      - Recording
        Third episode of the second season. First produced in Hollywood on July 17, 1945, under Corwin's direction. Groucho Marx played the Judge, Robert Benchley the Interpreter, Vincent Price was the Prosecutor, Normam [sic] Lloyd the Clerk, and Sylvia Sidney appeared as Miss Anima. Keenan Wynn performed four roles, quadrupling as Defense Counsel, Spokesman for the Vegetable and Mineral Kingdoms, and the Conductor. Elliott Lewis was Vice-president in Charge of Physio-Chemistry. The musical score was by Carmen Dragon and was conducted by Lud Gluskin. Published as one of the plays in UNTITLED AND OTHER RADIO DRAMAS, Henry Holt, 1947. A note on the sleeve's label indicates that additional references in Envelope No. 134. On the disc's label in red pen is written Set I. Also there is a note written in pen "Co 121".
        - The Undecided Molecule [disc 1 of 2], 07/17/1945; corwin_0173; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - The Undecided Molecule [disc 2 of 2], 07/17/1945; corwin_0174; Lacquer discs/acetates (Oversize 6)
      - Translation, Italian, undated (Box 23)
    - Unity Fair, Columbia Presents Corwin, Season 2 #1
      - Correspondence (122), 1945 (Box 23)
      - Recording, 1944
        The opening program of the second season of COLUMBIA PRESENTS CORWIN. It was broadcast from San Francisco, where Corwin had gone to produce WORD FROM THE PEOPLE, a broadcast commemorating the organizing conference of the United Nations. The cast included Alfred Drake, Groucho Marx, Burgess Meredith and June Richmond. Lyrics were by E. Y. Harburg, music by Burton Lane (the collaborators on FINIAN'S RAINBOW); a chorus was under the direction of Lud Gluskin. Presented on July 3, 1945, over CSB, under the author's direction. Unpublished. On the sleeve's label unfinished handwritten note reads: "Additional data in envelope". On the disc's label is printed "SETL I". Also there is a handwritten note "Co 107".
        - Unity Fair [disc 1 of 2], 07/03/1945; corwin_0175; Lacquer discs/acetates (Oversize 6)
        - Unity Fair [disc 2 of 2], 07/03/1945; corwin_0176; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, 1945
        Written, directed and produced by Corwin as the first of the second COLUMBIA PRESENTS CORWIN series, on July 3, 1945, from San Francisco, where the United Nations was sitting. Groucho Marx, Burgess meredith, and Alfred Drake headed the cast. E. Y. Harburg (who wrote the lyrics for FINIAN'S RAINBOW and other musicals) contributed special lyrics; Earl Robinson and Burton Lane write the music, though not in collaboration; Lud Gluskin conducted the orchestra and chorus. Script unpublished.
        - Unity Fair, part 1 of 2, 07/03/1945; corwin_0284; Lacquer discs/acetates (Oversize 8)
        - Unity Fair, part 2 of 2, 07/03/1945; corwin_0285; Lacquer discs/acetates (Oversize 8)
      - Script (122), 1945; mimeo, incomplete (Box 23)
    - Untitled, Columbia Presents Corwin, Season 1 #7
      - Recording, April 1944
        Presented over CBS on April 18, 1944, as the 7th of the COLUMBIA PRESENTS CORWIN series, and repeated five weeks later. Frederic March performed as Hank Peters, the Voice throughout. The author directed, as in all of the broadcasts of this series. The script was widely performed in stage adaptations throughout the country, and was one of the staples of the Army Special Services training program. Published as the title piece in UNTITLED AND OTHER RADIO DRAMAS. Reprinted in VOGUE, CORONET, and the newspaper PM. A note on the sleeve's label indicates that there is additional data: Envelopes 113, 144, 145. On the disc's label the date is 05/30/1944, also there is a handwritten note indicating that this is Corwin's copy.
        - Untitled [disc 1 of 2], April 18, 1944; corwin_0150; Lacquer discs/acetates (Oversize 4)
        - Untitled [disc 2 of 2], April 18, 1944; corwin_0151; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, May 1944
        Originally broadcast on April 18, 1944 as the 7th of the COLUMBIA PRESENTS CORWIN series. Enclosed copy is a repeat broadcast of May 30, 1944. Frederic March performed the role of Hank Peters. Others in the cast included Allan Devitt, Donna Keith, Joseph Julian, Paul Mann, Hester Sondergaard, Charme Allen, and Michael Ingram. Bernard Herrmann composed and conducted the score.
        - [Columbia Presents Corwin #7] [disc 1 of 2], May 30, 1944; corwin_0211; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - [Columbia Presents Corwin #7] [disc 2 of 2], May 30, 1944; corwin_0212; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - A Very Fine Type Girl, Columbia Presents Corwin, Season 1 #21
      - Recording
        Broadcast on August 8, 1944, as the 21st program of the first COLUMBIA PRESENTS CORWIN series. Featured in the cast were Robert Dryden, Kermit Murdock, Joe Julian, Paul Mann, Larry Haines, Eleanor Sherman, Hester Sondergaard, Walter Burke, Minerva Pious and Adelaide Klein. The score was composed and conducted by Alexander Semmler. On the disc's label there is a hand written note indicating that this is Corwin's copy.
        - A Very Fine Type Girl [disc 1 of 2], August 8, 1944; corwin_0116; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - A Very Fine Type Girl [disc 2 of 2], August 8, 1944; corwin_0117; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - A Walk With Nick, Columbia Presents Corwin, Season 2 #5
      - Correspondence (120), 1945; includes some production memoranda (Box 23)
      - Recording
        - A Walk With Nick [disc 1 of 2], 07/31/1945; corwin_0275; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - A Walk With Nick [disc 2 of 2], 07/31/1945; corwin_0276; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - We Hold These Truths
      - Correspondence, printed edition (55), 1942; 1961; Howell, Soskin edition which includes unauthorized changes to the text (Box 23)
      - Recording [copy 1]
        Broadcast over the four networks on December 15, 1941, under the direction of the author. It was written to commemorate the 150th anniversary of the ratification of the American Bill of Rights. Included in the cast were Edward Arnold, Lionel Barrymore, Walter Brennan, Bob Burns, Walter Huston, Marjorie Main, Edward G. Robinson, James Stewart, Rudy Vallee and Orson Welles. Bernard Herrmann composed and conducted the score. President Franklin D. Roosevelt spoke from Washington. Published in MORE BY CORWIN, pp 55-96.
        - We Hold These Truths Parts 1 and 3 [disc 1 of 2], December 15, 1941; corwin_0222; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - We Hold These Truths Parts 2 and 4 [disc 2 of 2], December 15, 1941; corwin_0223; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording [copy 2]
        Presented over the four networks on December 15, 1941, under the direction of the author, who also produced. It was written to commemorate the 150th anniversary of the ratification of the American Bill of Rights. Included in the cast were Edward Arnold, Lionel Barrymore, Walter Brennan, Bob Burns, Walter Huston, Marjorie Main, Edward G. Robinson, James Stewart, Rudy Vallee, and Orson Welles. Bernard Herrmann composed and conducted the score. President Franklin D. Roosevelt spoke from Washington. Published in MORE BY CORWIN. Additional data in Envelope 255.
        - We Hold These Truths [disc 1 of 2], December 15, 1941; corwin_0245; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - We Hold These Truths [disc 2 of 2], December 15, 1941; corwin_0246; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Whitman, An American Trilogy #3; Columbia Presents Corwin #16
      - Recording
        Broadcast on June 20, 1944 as the 16th program in the first Columbia Presents Corwin series. It starred Charles Laughton and featured John Dehner, Peggy Miller and Wally Maher. Bernard Herrmann composed and conducted the score. As with the other programs in the series, Corwin directed and produced. On the sleeve label there is a note that additional data is in Envelope 167. A hand written note on the disc's label indicates that the record is personal property of Norman Corwin.
        - Whitman [disc 1 of 2], 06/20/1944; corwin_0106; Lacquer discs/acetates (Oversize 2)
        - Whitman [disc 2 of 2], 06/20/1944; corwin_0107; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Windows on the World
      - Correspondence (123), 1951 (Box 23)
      - Publicity (123), 1951-1952 (Box 23)
      - Recording, on disc
        - Windows on the World [disc 1 of 3], 11/11/1951; corwin_0252; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - Windows on the World [disc 2 of 3], 11/11/1951; corwin_0253; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - Windows on the World [disc 3 of 3], 11/11/1951; corwin_0254; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, on reel tape
        - WINDOWS ON THE WORLD [reel 1 of 2], 11/04/1951; corwin_0363; 1/2 inch audio tape (Box 31)
        - WINDOWS ON THE WORLD [reel 2 of 2], 11/04/1951; corwin_0364; 1/2 inch audio tape (Box 31)
      - Recording, on cassette tape
        Typed description accompanying cassette tapes reads as follows: "First broadcast on Nov. 4, 1951, over the stations of the Mutual Broadcasting System, and later distributed by United Nations Radio, for whom Corwin wrote it, to most of the English-speaking world. Corwin directed a crew of UN radio personnel in the gathering of material, and wrote the narration for Douglas Fairbanks Jr. / The script is unpublished. At the time of this broadcast, the UN numbered less than 70 members."
        - Windows on the World [tape 1 of 2], 11/04/1951; corwin_0372; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 31)
        - Windows on the World [tape 2 of 2], 11/04/1951; corwin_0373; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 31)
      - Research notes and memoranda (123), 1951 (Box 23)
      - Script (123), 1951 (Box 23)
    - Wolfe, An American Trilogy #2; Columbia Presents Corwin #15
      - Recording
        Broadcast on June 16, 1944 as the 15th program in the first COLUMBIA PRESENTS CORWIN series. It starred Charles Laughton and featured Hans Conreid, Elliott Lewis, Janet Scott, Franklin Parker, Alfred Ryder, Joseph Forte and Peter Leeds. Bernard Herrmann composed and conducted a score considered by many to have been one of his finest achievements. On the disc's label there is a hand written note indicating that this is Corwin's copy, also the date on the disc's label is 06/13/1944.
        - Wolfe [disc 1 of 2], 06/16/1944; corwin_0118; Lacquer discs/acetates (Oversize 3)
        - Wolfe [disc 2 of 2], 06/16/1944; corwin_0119; Lacquer discs/acetates (Oversize 3)
    - Word From the People
      - Correspondence (132), 1945; correspondence, internal memoranda (Box 23)
      - Scripts (132), 1945; typescripts, probably incomplete (Box 23)
    - Words Without Music, Corwin's first series
      See also The Plot to Overthrow Christmas and They Fly Through the Air, which were part of this series.
      - Correspondence (119), 1938-1946; undated; 2 folders (Box 24)
      - Recording, episode number unknown
        Characters in and around Broadway and Times Square, observed and enacted by Eddie Mayehoff in a setting conceived by Corwin. This was Mayehoff's first appearance in radio or before a national audience. He later was prominent in TV, films, and on the stage. The script was never published. Broadcast on 1938.
        - Broadway Document Part One [disc 1 of 2], 04/09/1939; corwin_0167; Lacquer discs/acetates
          The right side of the sleeve's label is torn. The label's content might not be complete.On the disc's label the name of Eddie Mayehoff is spelled Edward Mayhoff. The printed date there is 04/09/1939. There is also a note in pen "AE 37."
        - Broadway Document Part Two [disc 2 of 2], 04/09/1939; corwin_0168; Lacquer discs/acetates
          The right side of the sleeve's label is torn. The label's content might not be complete. On the disc's label the name of Eddie Mayehoff is spelled Edward Mayhoff. The printed date there is 04/09/1939. There is also a note in pen "AE 38."
    - You Can Dream, Inc., Columbia Presents Corwin, Season 1 #6
      - Correspondence (121), 1944; undated (Box 24)
      - Recording
        Presented as the 6th of the first COLUMBIA PRESENTS CORWIN series on April 11, 1944. John Griggs performed as the V-P in Charge of Sales; Ralph Bell played the Esthete; Minerva Pious was Minnie; Samuel Rasykn [sic] was Dad; Joseph Julian and Ruth Gilbert appeared in the elevator scene, and Robert Trout and Harry Marble played themselves. Alexander Semmler composed and conducted the score. Published in UNTITLED AND OTHER RADIO DRAMAS. On the sleeve's label is written that additional data is in Envelope 121. There is a hand written note on the disc's label indicating that this is Corwin's copy.
        - You Can Dream, Inc. [disc 1 of 2], 04/11/1944; corwin_0128; Lacquer discs/acetates